Okay, so let's talk about the increasing
approaches to quality management, right?
What's the most expensive approach versus
the least expensive approach to quality?
Now, the most expensive
approach then to quality is naturally
going to be letting the
customer find the defect, right?
That is going to be the most expensive
approach.
A customer finds a defect.
So all the costs associated with that,
right?
You've built the product,
you deliver it to the
customer, now they're
finding all these issues.
So let's think about some of the costs.
Warranty work, loss of reputation, loss
of business, liabilities, recalls, right?
You have to recall the product.
That's a major expense.
Potential litigation claims.
And again, a major expense.
So that is a most expensive approach to
quality.
To letting the customer find a defect.
We should find the defect beforehand.
We don't want the customer to find the
issues.
We want to find the issues beforehand.
Before it gets to the hands of the
customer.
But customer finding the issues,
customer finding the defects, customer
finding the problems, we now have to fix
that, right?
We now have to fix our own reputation.
We now have to fix a bit of, try and
potentially overcome some loss of business.
That is all known as an external failure
cost.
And that is an external failure cost.
Now, a better approach then, right,
is for us to find the defects first.
So, focusing on quality control.
So, we, before we
deliver the product to the
customer, we test it
to see if it's working.
So we correct the defects before it's sent
to the customer.
However, quality control, or rather
focusing on quality control, is also an
expensive approach because what we're
doing in quality control, we are building
the product, we're testing it,
seeing seeing if it works.
If it doesn't work, we go back and fix it.
That's an expensive approach.
If the product isn't working, that is
known as an internal failure cost.
This is before it gets sent to the
customer.
It's known as an internal failure cost.
So a better approach than
that is to focus on the process,
looking at the output of each
individual process, making sure the
output of each process
is working correctly.
So focusing on quality assurance,
managing your quality.
There's one of the PIMBOP processes is
called manage quality.
A managed quality refers to quality
assurance, refers to the process.
So making sure then
that we are systematically
removing any issues from the process.
So the output of each process is going to
be defect-free.
So again, think of a production line.
I go all these machines, right?
So the first raw materials goes into the
first machine is producing a component.
We're testing that component.
Is it doing what it's supposed to be
doing?
Then it goes into the next machine and so
and so forth.
So if the machines are working correctly,
if the process is working correctly,
then the output of each process should be
defect-free.
So that's a much better
approach than just focusing
on, you know, just
focusing on quality control.
Now that doesn't mean we ignore quality
control.
No, absolutely not.
No, you have to test the product.
But we should also be looking at the
process as well.
We're trying to prevent issues from
occurring.
So that's a much better approach.
But then an even better
approach is to plan quality
right at the beginning
throughout the project.
So have a quality management process,
a good quality management process,
plan your quality management
process right at the
beginning, right, and utilize
that throughout the project.
So basically, anticipate
what potential issues
could occur and have
a process to deal with it.
So that overlaps then also with risk
management.
In risk management, we're trying to
identify potential issues that could occur.
When we get to risk, we'll talk about what
is risk.
A risk is an uncertainty.
It may or may not happen.
So we're trying to identify any potential
issues.
A potential issue is a risk.
It may or may not happen.
So risk and quality go hand in hand.
If you have a good risk management process
in place and generally you have a good
quality management process in place
because you're identifying any potential
issues that may occur and you have a plan
to either prevent those issues from
occurring or have a plan to deal with
those issues if they do occur.
So we want to plan our quality management
process right at the beginning.
We need to have a good quality management
plan in place.
And then an even better approach
than that is to have basically
incorporate a culture of quality
into the entire organization.
Not every organization gets
to this, but the organization's
culture should have an awareness
and commitment to quality.
So constantly then looking
for potential issues and quality
is drummed into them as part
of the organization's culture.
So these are the five increasing
approaches.
to cost of quality, cost of quality
management.
I said the most expensive approach,
letting the customer find the defect,
the least expensive
approach, we actually have
a culture of quality
within the organisation.